<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Portfolios on Mark LeBoeuf</title>
    <link>/portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Portfolios on Mark LeBoeuf</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy;2017 Mark LeBoeuf</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2017 19:41:01 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Flavors of Parallel Simulation</title>
      <link>/portfolio/two_flavors_of_parallelism/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2017 19:41:01 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/two_flavors_of_parallelism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tired of waiting around for your simulations to finish? Run them in parallel! This post covers two seperate ways to add parallelism to your R code.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Choosing a Fantasy Football Quarterback</title>
      <link>/portfolio/choosing_a_qb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/choosing_a_qb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Aaron Rodgers or Tom Brady? Carson Wentz or Drew Brees? Choosing the right Fantasy Football QB each week is challenging. To remove some of the guesswork from the decision-making process, I devised an approach that&amp;rsquo;s worked well over the past few seasons. Read on to learn more about using the Beta Distribution to pick your weekly starting QB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predicting First Year Fantasy Football Points in Rookies</title>
      <link>/portfolio/combine_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/combine_analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Drafting a rookie in Fantasy Football can be a risky move, but it can pay huge dividends if you happen to snag a diamond in the rough. After accounting for a player&amp;rsquo;s draft position, do physical attributes (height/weight) and combine performance (40 yard dash, bench press, etc.) provide any additional explanatory power of points scored during a player&amp;rsquo;s first NFL season? I&amp;rsquo;ll explore this question for rookie Running Backs and Wide Receivers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time Series Outlier Detection</title>
      <link>/portfolio/outlier_detection/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2017 19:41:01 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/outlier_detection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This post covers a straightforward approach to detecting and replacing outliers in time series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forecasting with External Regressors</title>
      <link>/portfolio/forecasting_regressors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 19:41:01 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/forecasting_regressors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This post focuses on some of my favorite things &amp;ndash; data, sports, and forecasting &amp;ndash; and will outline how to leverage external regressors when creating forecasts. We&amp;rsquo;ll do some webscraping in R and Python to create our dataset, and then forecast how many people will visit Tom Brady&amp;rsquo;s wikipedia page.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feature Selection for the Wine Connoisseur</title>
      <link>/portfolio/feature_selection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 19:41:01 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/feature_selection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Feature selection is an integral part of machine learning, and this post explores what happens when lots of irrelevant features are added into the modeling process. We&amp;rsquo;ll also identify which algorithms are affected the most by such features. These questions will be addressed as we build a classifier and try to predict which wines we&amp;rsquo;ll like based on their chemical properties. So pour yourself a glass of Pinot Noir and fire up your R terminal!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keras End-to-End Tutorial</title>
      <link>/portfolio/keras_walk_through_end_to_end/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 19:41:01 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/keras_walk_through_end_to_end/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most Keras tutorials I&amp;rsquo;ve come across outline the process of creating a Convolutional Neural Network (CNN) with built-in datasets. While this is a great place to begin, there&amp;rsquo;s a bit more involved in terms of pre-processing when starting out with just a bunch of pictures. This post provides a quick, end-to-end walkthrough of how to implement a CNN with Keras in Python from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monte Carlo Power Calculations for Mixed Effects Models</title>
      <link>/portfolio/monte_carlo_mixed_effects/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2017 19:41:01 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/monte_carlo_mixed_effects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s a dense title &amp;ndash; Monte Carlo Simulation, Power, Mixed-Effect models. Each of these topics could be their own post. However, I&amp;rsquo;m going to discuss their interrelations in the context of experimental power and keep everything high-level. The goal is to get an intuitive idea of how we can leverage simulation to provide sample size estimates for experiments with nested data.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Early Trend Detection</title>
      <link>/portfolio/early_trend_detection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 19:41:01 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/early_trend_detection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Identifying a trend before it starts is a major area of focus in the analytics realm, because it can inform key business decisions yet remains extremely difficult. This post outlines one trend-detection method in an effort to predict where a stock&amp;rsquo;s price will go in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random Forest Prediction Intervals</title>
      <link>/portfolio/random_forest_prediction_intervals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2017 19:41:01 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/random_forest_prediction_intervals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Take a stroll through the random forest to learn how to quantify uncertainty in your predictions with one of the more popular applied machine learning algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Exception Handling</title>
      <link>/portfolio/exception_handling/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2017 19:41:01 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/exception_handling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Exception handling is a critical component of any data science workflow. You write code. It breaks. You create exceptions. Repeat. From my experience, a point of confusion for new R users is how to handle exceptions, which I believe is more intuitive in Python (at least initially). This post provides a practical overview of how to handle exceptions in R by first illustrating the concept in Python.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Establishing Causality with Counterfactual Prediction</title>
      <link>/portfolio/counterfactual_prediction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 19:41:01 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/counterfactual_prediction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes a controlled experiment isn&amp;rsquo;t an option yet you want to establish causality. This post outlines a method for quantifying the effects of an intervention via counterfactual predictions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>